so why do we need computer architecture
we need it if we want to improve
performance
for some definition of performance which
can be speed at which the computation is
going on battery life the overall size
of the computer its weight energy
efficiency and so on so we want one or
more of these to become better than
before and another reason why we want
computer architecture is to improve some
abilities of the computer such as adding
3d graphics support adding debugging
support so developers can develop
more bug free programs improving
security etc so this is about making
computers faster smaller and cheaper
and this is about making new things
possible
we do this by taking improvements in
fabrication technology and in circuit
designs and figuring out how to
translate that into faster lighter
cheaper more secure etc
so this is
where we need computer architecture